

Alastair Farman

Web Developer, 3D Generalist, Retoucher, Photographer

EXPERIENCE

Retoucher & Photographer, Frontend Development Freelance

02/2022 - Present

Working for clients like YNAP (Net-a-Porter, Mr Porter), Urban Outfitters and photographers Mikael Johansson. & Domenico Landolfi, Freelance web development and design project for Grow With Pace Marketing.

Retoucher & Photographer Dr Martens (AIRWAIR INTL)

04/2019 - 02/2022

Assisted in establishing new in-house photography studio with studio manager, including creating retouch and photography workflows, processes and standards. Lead still life ecom art direction, on-model technical direction and image sign-off. Shot and retouched still life, model and creative ecom assets as well as direct and support freelance staff. Established 360 spins video process.

Senior Retoucher

ALLSAINTS

11/2017 - 03/2019

Directing and supporting up to 8 in-house and freelance retouchers to ensure quick asset delivery to a high standard. Establishing and managing image workflow from camera to website, and providing on-set technical support. Responsible for retouch quality control, providing feedback to studio and retouch teams and holding image sign-off meetings with VM Director and Art Director Supporting as a photographer for castings, wholesale, internal documents shoots and still life when necessary.

Digital Concessions Coordinator ALLSAINTS

06/2016 - 11/2017

Alongside retouch responsibilities, responsible for co-ordinating delivery of image assets to digital concessions partners as the business expanded into new markets.

Retoucher **ALLSAINTS**

11/2014 - 06/2016

Autograph Menswear 05/2012 - 11/2014

eCommerce Coordinator & Photographer

Ran the full eCommerce operations for a small independent men's fashion store, from photography through the CMS management and order fulfilment

07912859255

alastair.farman@gmail.com https://alastairfarman.com/ London, United Kindgdom

SUMMARY

As a retoucher and photographer with over 10 years experience in the e-commerce and fashion industry, I began to explore different career paths during the pandemic lockdown. I started learning the fundamentals of 3D, and before briefly flirting with UX design I found web development, starting The Odin Project's full stack curriculum in June 2022. Since then I have compounded on the basics I learned by exploring different facets of development, with the idea of incorporating my previous experience into my new career path.

SKILLS

Photoshop

Adobe Creative Suite

CaptureOne

Blender

Unreal Engine

React

Javascript

Three.js

HTML

CSS

Studio Lighting

3D lighting, modelling, texturing, animation, rendering and ci

Fashion, beauty, comp and still life retouch

Photo studio workflow

EDUCATION

Media

Sheffield Hallam University

2010

BA Communication and Media Studies

CERTIFICATES

The Odin Project (Full stack Javascript course)

10/2022 - Present

Arden School, Knowle 2005 10 GCSEs inc English Maths and Science